<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ricing on Aspect</title>
    <link>/tags/ricing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ricing on Aspect</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 16:08:41 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ricing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Icons in AwesomeWM</title>
      <link>/posts/desktop_icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 16:08:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/desktop_icons/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to say. A Linux user, with desktop icons on his desktop? Blasphemy! And you&amp;rsquo;re right. It is blasphemy. I still do it, though. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s not like my desktop looks like this.
That&amp;rsquo;s just wrong. I believe that as long as you put only what you really need on your desktop, it&amp;rsquo;s only slightly blasphemy. This is what my AwesomeWM desktop looks like:</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to say. A Linux user, with &lt;em&gt;desktop icons&lt;/em&gt; on his desktop? Blasphemy! And you&amp;rsquo;re right. It is blasphemy. I still do it, though. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s not like my desktop looks like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/hell.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hell&#34; title=&#34;Hell.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s just wrong. I believe that as long as you put only what you really need on your desktop, it&amp;rsquo;s only slightly blasphemy. This is what my AwesomeWM desktop looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/nice.png&#34; alt=&#34;nice&#34; title=&#34;Heaven.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, despite having &lt;em&gt;gags&lt;/em&gt; desktop icons on the screen, it still looks quite clean. I ran into a few snags while attempting to set up desktop icons in Awesome, so I decided to write a short blog post about the process&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, there are two file managers that I know of that support desktop icons out of the box, those being Nemo and PCManFM. I use Nemo, and I would use Nemo over PCManFM because it supports GTK3 as opposed to GTK2 and is still being actively maintained. Install Nemo with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo pacman -S nemo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nemo comes with a nifty little command called &lt;code&gt;nemo-desktop&lt;/code&gt; which adds the contents of &lt;code&gt;~/Desktop&lt;/code&gt; to your desktop. If you run it now, desktop icons will not appear. You need to turn them on with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gsettings set org.nemo.desktop show-desktop-icons true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would recommend putting &lt;code&gt;nemo-desktop&lt;/code&gt; in your startup script for convenience sake. The problem with using Awesome with this is that it treats &lt;code&gt;nemo-desktop&lt;/code&gt; as any other client, which means it can only be available on one tag, and not any others. I fixed this by adding a ghost tag that is not visible on the taglist as follows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;screen.connect_signal(&amp;#34;request::desktop_decoration&amp;#34;, function(s)
	awful.tag({ &amp;#34;1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;2&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;3&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;4&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;5&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;6&amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34; }, s, awful.layout.layouts[1])
end)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;and making &lt;code&gt;nemo-desktop&lt;/code&gt; sticky, which means it shows on all desktops&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruled.client.append_rule {
    id = &amp;#34;desktop&amp;#34;,
    rule_any = {
        class = {
        &amp;#34;Nemo-desktop&amp;#34;
        }
    },
    properties = { sticky = true, tag = &amp;#34; &amp;#34; }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;One downside (well, not really a downside for me) is that Nemo has it&amp;rsquo;s own root menu, which means you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to use your own root menu. This is fine by me because my root menu is still Awesome&amp;rsquo;s default root menu, and Nemo&amp;rsquo;s root menu is actually pretty good, integrating well with Nemo itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think desktop icons are really comfy, and add a little bit of uniqueness to a rice. Hopefully this post is easy enough to follow so that you can get started adding your own desktop icons.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catppuccin</title>
      <link>/posts/catppuccin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 23:20:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/catppuccin/</guid>
      <description>Catppuccin: My Favorite Colorscheme Catppuccin is a relatively new colorscheme. Released just about a year ago, Catppuccin has quickly grown to be one of the most popular colorschemes, up there with Gruvbox and Nord, my other two favorite colorschemes that I have used in the past. There are a few things that set Catppuccin apart from the rest, though.
1. It&amp;rsquo;s colorful. My two favorite colorschemes of all time are Nord and Catppuccin.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;catppuccin-my-favorite-colorscheme&#34;&gt;Catppuccin: My Favorite Colorscheme&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catppuccin is a relatively new colorscheme. Released just about a year ago, Catppuccin has quickly grown to be one of the most popular colorschemes, up there with Gruvbox and Nord, my other two favorite colorschemes that I have used in the past. There are a few things that set Catppuccin apart from the rest, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-its-colorful&#34;&gt;1. It&amp;rsquo;s colorful.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My two favorite colorschemes of all time are Nord and Catppuccin. What gives Catppuccin the edge over Nord in my opinion, though, is that it&amp;rsquo;s very colorful. In fact, that&amp;rsquo;s one of Catppuccin&amp;rsquo;s core values; color is better than no color. Or something like that. Nord, on the other hand, is relatively colorless. I absolutely love Nord&amp;rsquo;s background color, but the other colors in the pallete just don&amp;rsquo;t pop out to me as much. After about a year of daily driving a Nord machine, I came to realize; Nord is slightly depressing. It&amp;rsquo;s still a great colorscheme, it just lacks in color. If Catppuccin didn&amp;rsquo;t have as much color as it does, I would use Nord.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-a-huge-selection-of-ports&#34;&gt;2. A huge selection of ports.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catppuccin has, as far as I know, the most official ports out of any colorscheme other than Dracula and Solarized, coming in at a whopping total of 170 ports. Most of these ports are maintained by the community, but they all follow the same basic color pallete. There are Catppuccin ports for Neovim, Emacs, Polybar, Alacritty, even ST. Any program that you use, there&amp;rsquo;s likely a Catppuccin port for it, found over on the official Catppuccin repository over at
=&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/catppuccin/catppuccin&#34;&gt;https://github.com/catppuccin/catppuccin&lt;/a&gt; the Catppuccin GitHub page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-different-flavors-based-on-your-preferences&#34;&gt;3. Different flavors based on your preferences.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Catppuccin has four official flavors, the aptly named Mocha, Macchiato, Frappe, and Latte, ordered from darkest to lightest. Mocha, Macchiato and Frappe are the dark themes, while Frappe is Catppuccin&amp;rsquo;s light theme. I really love Mocha&amp;rsquo;s color pallete, and it&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m using on my system right now. It has a really nice dark blue background, and is contrasty enough to be easy to read but also extremely nice to look at. There are also some community flavors such as Oledpuccin, which is Catppuccin except black for OLED screens. It looks very nice, but I don&amp;rsquo;t have an OLED screen so I will probably never use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-a-large-variety-of-accent-colors&#34;&gt;4. A large variety of accent colors.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To add your own personal pop to Catppuccin, you can choose from one of 14 accent colors, ranging from rosewater to teal to blue to muave to lavender. My favorite accent color is the basic blue, though lavender is extremely nice as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-a-very-active-community&#34;&gt;5. A very active community.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike other colorschemes, Catppuccin&amp;rsquo;s community is still very much active and is spitting out new ports. It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to contribute to Catppuccin too, all you need to do is make a pull request on their Github.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
