<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>wm on Aspect</title>
    <link>onefractal.tech/tags/wm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in wm on Aspect</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 16:08:41 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="onefractal.tech/tags/wm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Icons in AwesomeWM</title>
      <link>onefractal.tech/posts/desktop_icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 16:08:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>onefractal.tech/posts/desktop_icons/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to say. A Linux user, with desktop icons on his desktop? Blasphemy! And you&amp;rsquo;re right. It is blasphemy. I still do it, though. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s not like my desktop looks like this.
That&amp;rsquo;s just wrong. I believe that as long as you put only what you really need on your desktop, it&amp;rsquo;s only slightly blasphemy. This is what my AwesomeWM desktop looks like:</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Yes, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to say. A Linux user, with &lt;em&gt;desktop icons&lt;/em&gt; on his desktop? Blasphemy! And you&amp;rsquo;re right. It is blasphemy. I still do it, though. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s not like my desktop looks like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;onefractal.tech/hell.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;hell&#34; title=&#34;Hell.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s just wrong. I believe that as long as you put only what you really need on your desktop, it&amp;rsquo;s only slightly blasphemy. This is what my AwesomeWM desktop looks like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;onefractal.tech/nice.png&#34; alt=&#34;nice&#34; title=&#34;Heaven.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, despite having &lt;em&gt;gags&lt;/em&gt; desktop icons on the screen, it still looks quite clean. I ran into a few snags while attempting to set up desktop icons in Awesome, so I decided to write a short blog post about the process&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First things first, there are two file managers that I know of that support desktop icons out of the box, those being Nemo and PCManFM. I use Nemo, and I would use Nemo over PCManFM because it supports GTK3 as opposed to GTK2 and is still being actively maintained. Install Nemo with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo pacman -S nemo
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nemo comes with a nifty little command called &lt;code&gt;nemo-desktop&lt;/code&gt; which adds the contents of &lt;code&gt;~/Desktop&lt;/code&gt; to your desktop. If you run it now, desktop icons will not appear. You need to turn them on with&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gsettings set org.nemo.desktop show-desktop-icons true
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would recommend putting &lt;code&gt;nemo-desktop&lt;/code&gt; in your startup script for convenience sake. The problem with using Awesome with this is that it treats &lt;code&gt;nemo-desktop&lt;/code&gt; as any other client, which means it can only be available on one tag, and not any others. I fixed this by adding a ghost tag that is not visible on the taglist as follows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;screen.connect_signal(&amp;#34;request::desktop_decoration&amp;#34;, function(s)
	awful.tag({ &amp;#34;1&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;2&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;3&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;4&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;5&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;6&amp;#34;, &amp;#34; &amp;#34; }, s, awful.layout.layouts[1])
end)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;and making &lt;code&gt;nemo-desktop&lt;/code&gt; sticky, which means it shows on all desktops&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ruled.client.append_rule {
    id = &amp;#34;desktop&amp;#34;,
    rule_any = {
        class = {
        &amp;#34;Nemo-desktop&amp;#34;
        }
    },
    properties = { sticky = true, tag = &amp;#34; &amp;#34; }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;One downside (well, not really a downside for me) is that Nemo has it&amp;rsquo;s own root menu, which means you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to use your own root menu. This is fine by me because my root menu is still Awesome&amp;rsquo;s default root menu, and Nemo&amp;rsquo;s root menu is actually pretty good, integrating well with Nemo itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think desktop icons are really comfy, and add a little bit of uniqueness to a rice. Hopefully this post is easy enough to follow so that you can get started adding your own desktop icons.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
