<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aspect</title>
    <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aspect</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://aspectsides.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 23:59:31 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Org Roam</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/orgroam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 23:59:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/orgroam/</guid>
      <description>Org Roam; The New best Notetaking Software for the Zettelkasten method Why not Obsidian? or Vimwiki? I have hopped notetaking software more times than I can count. When I first had the need to take notes, I did them in Google Docs and saved them to Google Drive. This was terrible, and I have no idea what by 13 year old self was doing. When I got slightly older and wiser, I discovered Evernote and transitioned over to that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Use Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/whyiusearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 17:05:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/whyiusearch/</guid>
      <description>5 Reasons why Arch Linux is the Best Linux Distribution What is Arch Linux? If you&amp;rsquo;ve been using Linux for any amount of time, you&amp;rsquo;ve likely heard of Arch Linux as the elitist&amp;rsquo;s Linux distro. This is due mainly to the fact that Arch used to be so goddamn hard to install. You had to go through all the trouble of installing drivers, a graphical environment and dependencies for said programs all through the TTY, without any graphical installation process to speak of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I installed Arch Linux on an M1 Macbook Air</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/asahilinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 16:20:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/asahilinux/</guid>
      <description>How I installed Arch Linux on an M1 Macbook Air What is Asahi Linux? Asahi Linux is an Arch-Based distribution of Linux that is specifically designed for use on MacBooks with Apple Silicon processors. It is, weirdly enough, faster than MacOS on the same hardware. As someone who&amp;rsquo;s only computer is an M1 MacBook Air, I have long been looking for something like this. I installed Asahi back in May of 2022, and it was not a great experience, mainly because of the inability to suspend the system and the lack of GPU drivers, which made it impossible to change the brightness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vimwiki</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/vimwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 23:43:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/vimwiki/</guid>
      <description>Why Vimwiki is the Best Notetaking Sofware What is Vimwiki? It&amp;rsquo;s a bit difficult to explain Vimwiki, but at its core, Vimwiki is a notetaking plugin for Vim that allows you to make your own personal wiki. It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to organize notes and create links between them. You can do so many things with Vimwiki, and Vimwiki has all but replaced Emacs Org Mode for me, as it is now much easier to organize my notes with Vimwiki than just shove all of my Org files in a directory in my home folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catppuccin</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/catppuccin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 23:20:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/catppuccin/</guid>
      <description>Catppuccin: My Favorite Colorscheme Catppuccin is a relatively new colorscheme. Released just about a year ago, Catppuccin has quickly grown to be one of the most popular colorschemes, up there with Gruvbox and Nord, my other two favorite colorschemes that I have used in the past. There are a few things that set Catppuccin apart from the rest, though.
1. It&amp;rsquo;s colorful. My two favorite colorschemes of all time are Nord and Catppuccin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
