<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Aspect</title>
    <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aspect</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://aspectsides.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 23:06:15 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aspectsides.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Desktop Icons in AwesomeWM</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/desktop_icons/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 23:06:15 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/desktop_icons/</guid>
      <description>Yes, I know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to say. A Linux user, with desktop icons on his desktop? Blasphemy! And you&amp;rsquo;re right. It is blasphemy. I still do it, though. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s not like my desktop looks like this.
That&amp;rsquo;s just wrong. I believe that as long as you put only what you really need on your desktop, it&amp;rsquo;s only slightly blasphemy. This is what my AwesomeWM desktop looks like:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Neovim for Editing LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/notes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2023 12:45:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/notes-1/</guid>
      <description>This is the first article in a three part series in which I discuss how I write math notes with LaTeX and Neovim.
Why I Started Using LaTeX One thing I&amp;rsquo;ve always recognized about myself is that I have terrible handwriting. Problem is, I&amp;rsquo;m a math major. I kinda need to be able to read my lecture notes later so I don&amp;rsquo;t fail the class. That&amp;rsquo;s when I discovered this blog post by Gilles Castel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Org Roam</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/orgroam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 23:59:31 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/orgroam/</guid>
      <description>Org Roam; The New best Notetaking Software for the Zettelkasten method Why not Obsidian? or Vimwiki? I have hopped notetaking software more times than I can count. When I first had the need to take notes, I did them in Google Docs and saved them to Google Drive. This was terrible, and I have no idea what by 13 year old self was doing. When I got slightly older and wiser, I discovered Evernote and transitioned over to that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 16:22:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>About Me Hey. My name is Daniel, and I&amp;rsquo;m a C++ dev and firmly believe in Emacs supremacy and am an open source evangalist. I use Arch Linux on a daily basis.
I also play Overwatch from time to time.
Contact me here.
I also have a Gemini space over at gemini://tilde.club/~aspect. Go check it out if you want.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vimwiki</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/vimwiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 23:43:35 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/vimwiki/</guid>
      <description>Why Vimwiki is the Best Notetaking Sofware What is Vimwiki? It&amp;rsquo;s a bit difficult to explain Vimwiki, but at its core, Vimwiki is a notetaking plugin for Vim that allows you to make your own personal wiki. It&amp;rsquo;s really easy to organize notes and create links between them. You can do so many things with Vimwiki, and Vimwiki has all but replaced Emacs Org Mode for me, as it is now much easier to organize my notes with Vimwiki than just shove all of my Org files in a directory in my home folder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catppuccin</title>
      <link>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/catppuccin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 23:20:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aspectsides.github.io/posts/catppuccin/</guid>
      <description>Catppuccin: My Favorite Colorscheme Catppuccin is a relatively new colorscheme. Released just about a year ago, Catppuccin has quickly grown to be one of the most popular colorschemes, up there with Gruvbox and Nord, my other two favorite colorschemes that I have used in the past. There are a few things that set Catppuccin apart from the rest, though.
1. It&amp;rsquo;s colorful. My two favorite colorschemes of all time are Nord and Catppuccin.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
